Guide to the Daily Worker and Daily World Cartoon Collection GRAPHICS.024.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
The Daily Worker and Daily World Cartoon Collection
1928-2002
1940-1980
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Ellis, Fred, 1885-1965
Communist Party of the United States of America
Harrington, Oliver W. (Oliver Wendell), 1912-1995
Erickson, James
Gellert, Hugo, 1892-1985
Minor, Robert, 1884-1952
Andrews, Bill, 1937-
Reference Center for Marxist Studies
Longview Publishing Company
GRAPHICS.024.001
18.75 Linear Feet in 6 records cartons, 1 manuscript box, and 9 oversize flat boxes.
The Daily Worker and Daily World Cartoon Collection contains a wide range of cartoons and sketches published and submitted for publication to the official organ of the Communist Party of the United States of America (CPUSA), the Daily Worker (and its various later forms). The Daily Worker's editorial positions reflected the policies of the CPUSA. The paper also attempted to speak to the broad left-wing community in the United States that included labor, civil rights, and peace activists, with stories covering a wide range of events, organizations and individuals in the United States and around the world. As a daily newspaper, it covered the major stories of the twentieth century. However, the paper always placed an emphasis on radical social movements, social and economic conditions particularly in working class and minority communities, poverty, labor struggles, racial discrimination, right wing extremism with an emphasis on fascist and Nazi movements, and of course the Soviet Union and the world-wide Communist movement. The paper has had a succession of names and has been published in varying frequences between daily to weekly over the course of its existence. In 2010 it ceased print publication and became an electronic, online-only, weekly publication titled the People's World. A number of different artists are represented in the collection, including: Fred Ellis, Eric (James Erickson), Hugo Gellert, Norman Goldberg, Ollie Harrington, Hal Kinkaid, Robert Minor, and Joseph Seymour, among numerous others. A large portion of the cartoons in the collection are original, signed drawings, but also present are newsprint copies and pre-press prints. The material in the collection ranges in date from the late 1920s up through the 2002, though is predominantly from the 1940s-1980s. The topics covered by the cartoons are as diverse as was the coverage of the Daily Worker. Focusing heavily on capitalism, civil rights, civil liberties, labor, and the Vietnam War, as well as caricatures of Presidents and other influential politicians, the cartoons provide a narrative for the major events of the 20th century, particularly those that effected the left-wing community in the US.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Related Archival Material
Bill Andrews Editorial Cartoons and Papers (GRAPHICS 038)
Communist Party of the United States of America Printed Ephemera Collection (PE 031)
Communist Party of the United States of America Records (TAM 132)
The Daily Worker and the Daily World Negatives Collection (PHOTOS 223.1)
The Daily Worker and the Daily World Photographs Collection (PHOTOS 223)
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in four series: I: Biographical Cartoons; II: Subject Cartoons; III: Cartoons by Artist; IV: Ephemera and other Graphics.
All series are arranged first alphabetically and then chronologically. Due to space constraints, physical arrangement of materials does not match intellectual arrangement.
Scope and Content Note
The Daily Worker and Daily World Cartoon Collection consists of original and copied cartoons and sketches produced for the Daily Worker/Daily World and its later incarnations. There is a small amount of non-cartoon graphics and ephemera in the collection. The material ranges in date from 1928-2002, but is largely from the 1940s-1980s. The Collection is arranged into four series, the first two of which were pulled from the Daily Worker and Daily World Photograph Collection (PHOTOS 223). Like that Collection, here there is a Biographical Series, which includes cartoons depicting individuals, and a Subject Series. The cartoons in these two series are as diverse as the topics covered by the newspaper, including in the Biographical Series prominent radical and progressive leaders, as well as US Presidents, labor leaders, and cultural figures. The subjects, too, are diverse and cover not only major issues facing communists such as capitalism and labor, civil liberties, McCarthyism and witch hunts, and struggles for peace but also a wide range of everyday images as well, such as beaches, children, education, and holidays.
Included in the Collection are cartoons, both original and copies, from several prominent artists. These include: Fred Ellis, Eric (James Erickson), Norman Goldberg, Ollie Harrington, Hal Kincaid, Robert Minor, among dozens more. There are enough cartoons by each artist, that his/her general but unique style is conveyed. Of particular note are the hundreds of original sketches and drawings from Fred Ellis as well as scrapbooks of his printed cartoons. There is a small sketchbook from Robert Minor, a signature from Hugo Gellert, and a signed sketch from Pete Seeger.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Daily Worker, the official organ of the Communist Party of the United States of America (CPUSA), traces its origins back to the Communist Labor Party, founded in Chicago in 1919. The Communist Labor Party's paper was known as the Toiler. When the Communist Labor Party and the Workers Party merged in 1921, the Toiler became the weekly paper The Worker. Two years later, the paper changed its name to the Daily Worker. As a daily newspaper, the Daily Worker covered the major stories of the 20th century, while at the same time speaking to the left-wing sector of the American population, which included labor, civil rights, and peace activists. The newspaper emphasized radical social movements, labor struggles, racial discrimination, right wing extremism, the Soviet Union, and the world-wide Communist movement.
The CPUSA grew under increasing attack following WWII. The rise of McCarthyism and the Red Scare eventually forced the Party to go underground, and in 1958, the Daily Worker shut down operation. In 1960, it resumed bi-weekly publication as The Worker, but never achieved the level of popularity it had in the 1930s and 1940s.
In 1967, the paper now known as the Daily World, again became a daily. It reported on the civil rights movement, including sit-ins, voter registration campaigns and the Freedom Rides. In the late 1960s and into the early 1970s, the Daily World aligned itself with the anti-Vietnam War and black nationalist movements.
In 1986 the paper merged with the CPUSA's West Coast weekly, the People's World. The newly formed People's Daily World was published from 1987 until 1991, when daily publication was abandoned in favor of a weekly edition, renamed the People's Weekly World. During this period the paper focused heavily on labor union activity, particularly in cities like Detroit and Chicago, as well as the growing anti-globalization movement.
Shifting its operations back to Chicago between 2001 and 2002, the paper changed its name to the People's World in 2009. In 2010, the paper ceased print publication and became an electronic, online-only, publication.
Specific artists represented in the Daily Worker/ Daily World Cartoon Collection include: Fred Ellis, Ollie Harrington, Hugo Gellert, Norman Goldberg, Kinkaid, and James Erickson (Eric), among numerous others.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The bulk of the Daily Worker and Daily World Cartoon Collection was transferred to the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives as part of the donation of the Communist Party of the USA archives and the Library of the Reference Center for Marxist Studies in the summer of 2006. Series I and II came directly out of the Daily Worker and Daily World Photographs Collection (PHOTOS 223), that collection too came in with the CPUSA donation in 2006. The accession numbers 2006.042 is associated with these materials. A small number of cartoons were donated by Sam Darcy's daughter in 2007. The accession number NPA.2007.029 is associated with this gift. A final donation of cartoons was made by Bill Andrews in 2011. The bulk of this gift is the Bill Andrews Editorial Cartoons and Papers (GRAPHICS 038). Artwork created by other artists for publication in the Daily Worker, The Worker and the Daily World were separated to this collection. The accession number 2011.120 is associated with this gift.
Elections -- United States -- History -- 20th century.; Communists |v Portraits.; Communism -- Newspapers.; Communism and art -- United States.; Communism -- United States -- 20th century; Communism -- United States.; Civil rights movements -- United States.; Civil rights -- United States.; Cartoonists -- United States; Anti-war demonstrations |z United States |v Pictorial works.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Art -- Political aspects.; Printed ephemera.; African Americans -- Civil rights.; Labor movement -- United States -- Pictorial works.; Labor leaders -- United States.; Labor unions and communism -- United States.; Labor movement -- United States.; Peace movements -- United States.; Labor unions |z United States |v Pictorial works.; Political cartoons -- United States.; Drawings (visual works); Caricatures and cartoons.; Daily world (New York, N.Y.); Daily Worker (New York); Andrews, Bill, 1937-; Reference Center for Marxist Studies; Longview Publishing Company; Communist Party of the United States of America
- Series I: Biographical Cartoons, 1936-1994
  Scope and Content Note
  Series I: Biographical Cartoons consists of cartoons depicting individuals. The cartoons were pulled from the Daily Worker and Daily World Photograph Collection (PHOTOS 223). The folder titles that the cartoons came out of were retained in this series. The material ranges in date from 1936-1994, but for the most part is undated. This series consists of original and pre-press drawings. Roughly half the folders contain signed artwork. Artists that have considerable representation in this series include: Eric (James Erickson), Hayle, Sam Hill, Hal Kinkaid, and Snow (Haile Hendrix). Individuals represented in the cartoons are diverse and range from US Presidents, Eisenhower, Johnson, Nixon, and Roosevelt to Communist Party USA leaders Benjamin Davis, Gil Green, and Gus Hall. Additionally, prominent cultural figures can also be found in this series as well as international political leaders. The people in the biographical series are as diverse as the Daily Worker/Daily World's coverage.
  - Barnes, Peter, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bartel, Maya, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Barton, Bruce, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Baruch, Bernard M. (Bernard Mannes), 1947, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Batista y Zaldivar, Fulgencio, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Beame, Abraham D. (Abraham David), 1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Beaverbrook, Max Aitken, Baron, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bedacht, Max, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bedaux, Charles Eugene, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Begun, Isadore, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Belfage, Cedric, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Benes, Edvard, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Benson, Elmer Austin, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Benson, Ezra Taft, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Bentley, Elizabeth, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bevin, Ernest, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bethune, Norman, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bidault, Georges, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Biddle, Francis, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Bilbo, Theodore, 1946, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Bittner, Van A., undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Bloice, Carl, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Bloom, Sol, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Blum, Leon, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Bondi, August, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bonnet, Georges, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Bonosky, Philip, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Boyle, William Anthony, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Bracetti, Mariana, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Brady, Robert A. (Robert Alexander), undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Brennan, Peter J., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Bridges, Harry, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Brooks, C. Weyland, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Brophy, John, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Broun, Heywood, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Brown, Clyde, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Brown, Ray, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Brownwell, Herbert, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Buck, Tim, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Budenz, Louis F. (Louis Francis), undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Burke, Kenneth, undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Burns, Robert, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1938-1940, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Byrd, Harry Flood, 1939, undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Byrnes, James F. (James Francis), undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Cadogan, Alexander, Sir, undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Campbell, Grace, undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Campora, Hector J., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Carmona, Antonio Oscar de Fragoso, undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Carey, James B., undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Carol II, King of Romania, undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Chamberlain, Neville, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Chandler, Happy, undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Chaplin, Charlie (as "The Tramp"), undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Chekov, Anton, undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Chiang, Kai-Shek, undated (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Churchill, Winston, 1938, undated (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Clark, Bennett Champ, 1943, undated (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Clark, Mark W. (Mark Wayne), undated (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Clark, Tom C. (Tom Campbell), undated (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Clay, Lucius D. (Lucius Du Bignon), undated (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Clifford, Clark M., undated (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Cohen, Sam "Chowder Head", undated (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Connally, Tom, 1946, undated (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Connolly, James, undated (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Codovilla, Victorio, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Coudert, Frederic R. (Frederic Rene) Jr., undated (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Coughlin, Charles E. (Charles Edward), undated (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Cox, Edward E. (Edward Eugene), undated (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Crane, Stephen, undated (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Crawford, Frederick C., undated (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Cripps, Richard Stafford, Sir, undated (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Crump, Edward Hull, undated (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Cunhal, Alvaro, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Curran, Joseph Edwin, undated (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Curry, John F., undated (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Davey, Martin L. (Martin Luther), undated (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Davis, Angela (in GDR at World Youth Festival), 1974 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Davis, Benjamin J. (Benjamin Jefferson), undated (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - De Gasperi, Alcide, undated (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - De Gaulle, Charles, undated (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - De Valera, Eamonn, undated (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Dewey, Thomas E. (Thomas Edmund), undated (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Diamond, Abby, undated (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Diaz, Jose, undated (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Dickinson, Luren Dudley, undated (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Dies, Martin, undated (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Diggs, Charles C., undated (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Dirksen, Everett McKinley, undated (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Dos Passos, John, undated (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Douglas, Henry Gahagan, undated (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Du Pont, Lammot, undated (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Du Sable, Jean Baptiste Pointe, undated (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Dubinsky, David, undated (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Duclos, Jaques, undated (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Duff, James H. (James Henderson), undated (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Dulles, John Foster I, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Dulles, John Foster II, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 97a)
  - Earle, George H. (George Howard), undated (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Eastland, James O. (James Oliver), undated (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Eccles, Marriner S. (Marriner Stoddard), undated (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Eden, Anthony, Earl of Avon, undated (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David) I, undated (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David) II, undated (Box 1, Folder 102a)
  - Elizabeth, Queen, Consort of George VI, King of Great Britain, undated (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - Emerson, Ralph Waldo, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 104)
  - Eisler, Gerhart, undated (Box 1, Folder 105)
  - Engels, Friedrich, undated (Box 1, Folder 106)
  - Erhard, Ludwig, undated (Box 1, Folder 107)
  - Ernst, Hugo, undated (Box 1, Folder 108)
  - Fairless, Benjamin F. (Benjamin Franklin), undated (Box 1, Folder 109)
  - Fast, Howard, undated (Box 1, Folder 110)
  - Ferber, Edna, undated (Box 1, Folder 111)
  - Ferre, Luis Alberto, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 112)
  - Feuchtwanger, Lion, undated (Box 1, Folder 113)
  - Fielding, Henry, undated (Box 1, Folder 114)
  - Finletter, Thomas K., undated (Box 1, Folder 115)
  - Fish, Hamilton, undated (Box 1, Folder 116)
  - Forrestal, James, undated (Box 1, Folder 117)
  - Foster, William Z., undated (Box 1, Folder 118)
  - Franco, Francisco, 1948, undated (Box 1, Folder 119)
  - Freud, Sigmund, undated (Box 1, Folder 120)
  - Friedlander, Ray, undated (Box 1, Folder 121)
  - Fulmer, Hampton Pitts, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 122)
  - Gabrielson, Guy George, undated (Box 1, Folder 123)
  - Garibaldi, Giuseppe, undated (Box 1, Folder 124)
  - Garner, John Nance, 1939, undated (Box 1, Folder 125)
  - Gates, John, undated (Box 1, Folder 126)
  - Gehrig, Lou, undated (Box 1, Folder 127)
  - George, Walter F., undated (Box 1, Folder 128)
  - Gershwin, George, undated (Box 1, Folder 129)
  - Gerson, Simon W., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 130)
  - Giannini, Amadeo Peter, undated (Box 1, Folder 131)
  - Giannani, L.M., undated (Box 1, Folder 132)
  - Gissible, Fritz, undated (Box 1, Folder 133)
  - Gitlow, Benjamin, undated (Box 1, Folder 134)
  - Giraud, Henri, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 135)
  - Gladwin, Hubert Miles Gladwyn Jebb, Baron, undated (Box 1, Folder 136)
  - Glass, Carter, undated (Box 1, Folder 137)
  - Geogeels, Joseph, undated (Box 1, Folder 138)
  - Goefel, Hans, undated (Box 1, Folder 139)
  - Gold, Ben, undated (Box 1, Folder 140)
  - Goldstein, Jonah J., 1945 (Box 1, Folder 141)
  - Goldwater, Barry M. (Barry Morris), 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 142)
  - Graham, Martha, undated (Box 1, Folder 143)
  - Gray, Gordon, undated (Box 1, Folder 144)
  - Green, Gil, undated (Box 1, Folder 145)
  - Green, William, undated (Box 1, Folder 146)
  - Gregory, Dick, undated (Box 1, Folder 147)
  - Guo, Muruo, undated (Box 1, Folder 148)
  - Gromyko, Andrei Andreevich, undated (Box 1, Folder 149)
  - Groves, Leslie R., undated (Box 1, Folder 150)
  - Grundy, Joseph R. (Joseph Ridgeway), undated (Box 1, Folder 151)
  - Hague, Frank, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 152)
  - Halifax, Edward Frederick Lindley Wood, Earl of, undated (Box 1, Folder 153)
  - Hall, Gus, undated (Box 1, Folder 154)
  - Halley, Rudolph, undated (Box 1, Folder 155)
  - Hamilton, Alexander, undated (Box 1, Folder 156)
  - Hand, Learned, undated (Box 1, Folder 157)
  - Hanley, Joe R., undated (Box 1, Folder 158)
  - Hannegan, Robert J., undated (Box 1, Folder 159)
  - Harriman, W. Averell (William Averell), undated (Box 1, Folder 160)
  - Harrington, F. C., 1939 (Box 1, Folder 161)
  - Hart, Merwin Kimball, undated (Box 1, Folder 162)
  - Hays, Will H. (William Harrison), undated (Box 1, Folder 163)
  - Hearst, William Randolph, undated (Box 1, Folder 164)
  - Heil, Julius P., 1939 (Box 1, Folder 165)
  - Hemingway, Ernest, undated (Box 1, Folder 166)
  - Heywood, Alan S., undated (Box 1, Folder 167)
  - Hikmet, Nazim, undated (Box 1, Folder 168)
  - Hill, Lister, undated (Box 1, Folder 169)
  - Hillman, Sydney, undated (Box 1, Folder 170)
  - Hitler, Adolf, undated (Box 1, Folder 171)
  - Hiss, Alger, undated (Box 1, Folder 172)
  - Ho Chi Minh, undated (Box 1, Folder 173)
  - Hobby, Oveta Culp, undated (Box 1, Folder 174)
  - Hoffman, Harold Giles, undated (Box 1, Folder 175)
  - Holt, Rush Dew, undated (Box 1, Folder 176)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1943, undated (Box 1, Folder 177)
  - Hoover, J. Edgar (John Edgar), undated (Box 1, Folder 178)
  - Hore-Belisha, Leslie, Baron, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 179)
  - Houdek, Vladimir, undated (Box 1, Folder 180)
  - Howard, Roy, undated (Box 1, Folder 181)
  - Huggins, Ericka, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 182)
  - Hull, Cordell, undated (Box 1, Folder 183)
  - Humphrey, George M. (George Magoffin), undated (Box 1, Folder 184)
  - Humphrey, Hubert H. (Hubert Horatio), undated (Box 1, Folder 185)
  - Hunt, H.L., undated (Box 1, Folder 186)
  - Hurley, Patrick J. (Patrick Jay), undated (Box 1, Folder 187)
  - Hussein, King of Jordan, undated (Box 1, Folder 188)
  - Ibarruri, Dolores, undated (Box 1, Folder 189)
  - Ickes, Harold L. (Harold LeClair), 1938 (Box 1, Folder 190)
  - Impelletteri, Vincent R. (Vincent Richard), undated (Box 1, Folder 191)
  - Ingersoll, Ralph, undated (Box 1, Folder 192)
  - Jackson, Andrew, undated (Box 1, Folder 193)
  - Jackson, James E., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 194)
  - Jiang, Qing, undated (Box 1, Folder 195)
  - Johnson, Hugh S., undated (Box 1, Folder 196)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 197)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1967, undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Jones, Jesse H., undated (Box 1, Folder 198)
  - Kefauver, Estes, undated (Box 1, Folder 199)
  - Keller, Helen, undated (Box 1, Folder 200)
  - Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), undated (Box 1, Folder 201)
  - Kennedy, Joseph P. (Joseph Patrick), undated (Box 1, Folder 202)
  - Kennelly, Martin H., 1949 (Box 1, Folder 203)
  - Kenyatta, Jomo, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 204)
  - King, William Henry, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 205)
  - Kinsey, Alfred C., undated (Box 1, Folder 206)
  - Kuauth, Oswald Whitman, undated (Box 1, Folder 207)
  - Knowland, William F. (William Fife), undated (Box 1, Folder 208)
  - Knowlson, James S., 1949 (Box 1, Folder 209)
  - Knox, Frank, undated (Box 1, Folder 210)
  - Knudsen, William S., undated (Box 1, Folder 211)
  - Komarov, V. L. (Vladimir Leontievich), undated (Box 1, Folder 212)
  - LaGuardia, Fiorella H. (Fiorella Henry), 1938, undated (Box 1, Folder 213)
  - Lautner, John, undated (Box 1, Folder 214)
  - Laval, Pierre, 1942, undated (Box 1, Folder 215)
  - Le Suer, Meridel, undated (Box 1, Folder 216)
  - Leahy, William D., 1943 (Box 1, Folder 217)
  - Lefkowitz, Louis J., undated (Box 1, Folder 218)
  - Lehman, Herbert H. (Herbert Henry), 1938, undated (Box 1, Folder 219)
  - Lemke, William, undated (Box 1, Folder 220)
  - Lermontov, Mikhail Iurevich, undated (Box 1, Folder 221)
  - Levine, Ben, undated (Box 1, Folder 222)
  - Levine, Sam, undated (Box 1, Folder 223)
  - Lewis, David J., undated (Box 1, Folder 224)
  - Lewis, Denny, undated (Box 1, Folder 225)
  - Lewis, John Llewellyn, 1943-1975, undated (Box 1, Folder 226)
  - Libonati, Roland V., 1949 (Box 1, Folder 227)
  - Lillian, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 228)
  - Lincoln, Abraham, 1967, undated (Box 1, Folder 229)
  - Lindbergh, Anne Morrow, undated (Box 1, Folder 230)
  - Lindbergh, Charles A. (Charles Augustus), undated (Box 1, Folder 231)
  - Lindsay, John V. (John Vliet), undated (Box 1, Folder 232)
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot, Jr., 1969, undated (Box 1, Folder 233)
  - Louis, Joe, undated (Box 1, Folder 234)
  - Lovell, Robert A. (Robert Abercrombie), undated (Box 1, Folder 235)
  - Lovett, Robert Morss, circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 236)
  - Luce, Clare Boothe, undated (Box 1, Folder 237)
  - Maas, Melvin Joseph, undated (Box 1, Folder 238)
  - MacArthur, Douglas, undated (Box 1, Folder 239)
  - Macmillan, Harold, undated (Box 1, Folder 240)
  - Malenkov, Georgi Maksimilianovich, undated (Box 1, Folder 241)